<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Maximilian Holzmüller</title>
        <link>https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Maximilian Holzmüller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <atom:link href="https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>High School</title>
            <link>https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/1/01/high-school/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/1/01/high-school/</guid>
            <description>Details  Institution: Gymnasium bei St. Anna, Augsburg, Germany
Duration: September 2008 - June 2016 (8 years)
GPA: 2.5 (German high school scale)
About my High School Education  My high school&amp;rsquo;s education was focused on the humanities and offered a wide variety of classes. However, the focus was clearly on languages and social sciences but not limited to those.
Most memorably, my school offered amazing extracurricular activities that taught me valuable lessons for life.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="details">Details</h1>
<hr>
<p>Institution: Gymnasium bei St. Anna, Augsburg, Germany</p>
<p>Duration: September 2008 - June 2016 (8 years)</p>
<p>GPA: 2.5 (German high school scale)</p>
<h1 id="about-my-high-school-education">About my High School Education</h1>
<hr>
<p>My high school&rsquo;s education was focused on the humanities and offered a wide variety of classes. However, the focus was clearly on languages and social sciences but not limited to those.</p>
<p>Most memorably, my school offered amazing extracurricular activities that taught me valuable lessons for life. In one of my classes, we crossed the alps with mountain bikes (8 days) which required rigorous planning, endurance and technique practice over the course of two years. It has taught me exceptional interpersonal and team working skills and the importance of collaboration.</p>
<p>The following list demonstrates the broad range of my high school education (numbers of years taught):</p>
<h1 id="stem">STEM</h1>
<ul>
<li>Mathematics (8)</li>
<li>Biology (7)</li>
<li>Physics (4)</li>
<li>Chemistry (3)</li>
<li>Exercise Science (2)</li>
<li>Computer Science (2)</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="languages">Languages</h1>
<ul>
<li>German (8)</li>
<li>English (7)</li>
<li>Latin (6)</li>
<li>Italian (3)</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="social-sciences">Social Sciences</h1>
<ul>
<li>History (8)</li>
<li>Ethics &amp; Religions (7)</li>
<li>Geography (6)</li>
<li>Sociology (2)</li>
<li>Economics &amp; Law (2)</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="other">Other</h1>
<ul>
<li>Physical Education (8)</li>
<li>Arts (8)</li>
<li>Music (6)</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Bachelor in Finance and Economics</title>
            <link>https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/1/01/bachelor-in-finance-and-economics/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/1/01/bachelor-in-finance-and-economics/</guid>
            <description>Details  Institution: University of Arkansas at Little Rock, USA
Duration: August 2017 - May 2020
GPA: 3.88
Institutional Honors: Magna Cum Laude
Academic Awards Pages
 Institution: Cardinal Stritch University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA
Duration: August 2016 - May 2017 (Freshman year)
GPA: 3.92
Relevant Courses  My degrees&#39; most relevant and interesting courses that helped me shape my understanding of Financial and Economic principles and develop business acumen.
Finance Financial Modeling</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="details">Details</h2>
<hr>
<p>Institution: University of Arkansas at Little Rock, USA</p>
<p>Duration: August 2017 - May 2020</p>
<p>GPA: 3.88</p>
<p>Institutional Honors: Magna Cum Laude</p>
<p><a href="http://meritpages.com/maxholzmueller">Academic Awards Pages</a></p>
<hr>
<p>Institution: Cardinal Stritch University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA</p>
<p>Duration: August 2016 - May 2017 (Freshman year)</p>
<p>GPA: 3.92</p>
<h2 id="relevant-courses">Relevant Courses</h2>
<hr>
<p>My degrees' most relevant and interesting courses that helped me shape my understanding of Financial and Economic principles and develop business acumen.</p>
<h3 id="finance">Finance</h3>
<p>Financial Modeling</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Solved hands-on financial problems using advanced Excel functions to build practical models.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investment Analysis</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Alternative investment opportunities, analysis of the economy, its industries, and particular businesses to determine the most desirable use of funds in terms of the objectives of individual and institutional investment programs.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Financial Markets</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Examination and analysis of financial markets, such as savings institutions, banks, insurance companies, mutual funds, pension funds, and others.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Accounting</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Fundamentals of financial accounting, recording, summarizing, and reporting cycle. Principles of asset valuation and income measurement; accounting systems and internal controls. Reporting for external investors. Management accounting and decision making.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="economics">Economics</h3>
<p>Econometrics</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Data collection, model specification, regression analysis, violations of regression assumptions and corrections, indicator variables, linear restrictions tests, and limited dependent variable models. Used R software to assist a public policy institute in decision making and advocacy efforts.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Microeconomics</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Price and production theory. Consumer demand, the supply function, market pricing, and various degrees of competition.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Macroeconomics</p>
<blockquote>
<p>National income analysis and its implications for public policy; its historical development and present status, including recent business cycle development.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="management">Management</h3>
<p>Business strategy</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Integration of business concepts and techniques and their application to the development of corporate strategy and strategic planning by senior corporate executives. Includes setting objectives, developing business purposes, determining opportunities and threats, and implementing decision and control systems across functional areas.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Risk Management</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Introduction to the fundamentals of risk management. Scope and fundamentals of property and liability insurance; analysis of contracts, rating, underwriting, insurers, and loss adjustments and procedures.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Production Management</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Topics are selected from project management, operations strategy, quality management, inventory management, capacity planning, theory of constraints, transportation/ assignment problems, and an introduction to supply chain management.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="mathematics">Mathematics</h3>
<p>Business Statistics 1 and 2</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Foundations such multiple regression and correlation, goodness of fit, chi square and tests of independence, decision analysis and expected values, analysis of variance, sampling techniques, forecasting, decomposing a time series, and nonparametric tests.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Applied Calculus</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Differential and integral calculus of algebraic, exponential, and logarithmic functions with applications to economics, management sciences, engineering technology, and the life sciences</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Bachelor in Business Analytics</title>
            <link>https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/1/01/bachelor-in-business-analytics/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://mohol98.github.io/Max_Website/posts/1/01/bachelor-in-business-analytics/</guid>
            <description>Details  Institution: University of Arkansas at Little Rock, USA
Duration: August 2020 - May 2021
Academic Awards Pages
Relevant Courses  The following courses are the most interesting and relevant courses in my one-year postbaccalaureate program.
Analytics Predictive Analytics
 Using statistical methods (Multiple Regression, ANOVA, Logistic Regression, Quantile Regression, ARIMA) and statistical tools (R and Python) to predict financial and economic outcomes.
 Marketing Research
 Using Python and R to predict and test marketing outcomes (A/B testing, Multiple Regression, Clustering, T-Testing).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="details">Details</h2>
<hr>
<p>Institution: University of Arkansas at Little Rock, USA</p>
<p>Duration: August 2020 - May 2021</p>
<p><a href="http://meritpages.com/maxholzmueller">Academic Awards Pages</a></p>
<h2 id="relevant-courses">Relevant Courses</h2>
<hr>
<p>The following courses are the most interesting and relevant courses in my one-year postbaccalaureate program.</p>
<h3 id="analytics">Analytics</h3>
<p>Predictive Analytics</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Using statistical methods (Multiple Regression, ANOVA, Logistic Regression, Quantile Regression, ARIMA) and statistical tools (R and Python) to predict financial and economic outcomes.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Marketing Research</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Using Python and R to predict and test marketing outcomes (A/B testing, Multiple Regression, Clustering, T-Testing).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Database Management Systems</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Principles of database design, data manipulation, and data retrieval from commercial database systems (SQL Server, Oracle).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Data Analysis and Reporting</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Advanced database techniques and data visualization, data warehousing, reporting, and other BI tools to solve business problems (Power BI, Tableau).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Big Data Analytics Tools</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Extracting information from large databases and designing decision support systems. Summarizing, Predicting, and Explaining of observed phenomena such as patterns, trends, and consumer behavior (Power BI, SQL Server, Hadoop).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Information Systems Development Project</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Developing a working information system, combining all methods and tools from the Business Analytics coursework.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="programming">Programming</h3>
<p>Object-Oriented Programming</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Introduction to object oriented programming using Java to build basic applications.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Advanced Programming</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Using programming techniques to built practical business applications to automate processes.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
